Everything is connected
Cloud Atlas is a drama, science fiction film directed by Lana Wachowski.
A set of six nested stories spanning time between the 19th
century and a distant post-apocalyptic future.
Cloud Atlas explores how the actions and consequences of individual lives
impact one another throughout the past, the present and the future.
Action, mystery and romance weave through the story as one soul is shaped from a killer into a hero and a
single act of kindness ripples across centuries to inspire a revolution in the distant future.
Based on the award winning novel by David Mitchell.
Directed by Tom Tykwer and the Wachowskis.
Dr. Henry Goose / Hotel Manager / Isaac Sachs / Dermot Hoggins /
Cavendish Look-a-Like Actor / Zachry, played by Tom Hanks.
Native Woman / Jocasta Ayrs / Luisa Rey / Indian Party
Guest / Ovid / Meronym, played by Halle Berry.
Captain Molyneux / Vyvyan Ayrs / Timothy Cavendish / Korean
Musician / Prescient 2, played by Jim Broadbent.
Haskell Moore / Tadeusz Kesselring / Bill Smoke / Nurse Noakes /
Boardman Mephi / Old Georgie, played by Hugo Weaving.
Adam Ewing / Poor Hotel Guest / Megan's Dad / Highlander / Hae-Joo Chang
/ Adam / Zachry Brother-in-Law, played by Jim Sturgess.
Tilda / Megan's Mom / Mexican Woman / Sonmi-451 / Sonmi-351
/ Sonmi Prostitute, played by Bae Doona.
Cloud Atlas is a 2012 epic science fiction film written and
directed by the Wachowskis and Tom Tykwer.
Based on the 2004 novel by David Mitchell, it has multiple plots occurring during six eras and
features an ensemble cast who perform multiple roles across these time periods.
The film was produced by Grant Hill and Stefan Arndt, in
addition to the Wachowskis and Tykwer.
During its four years of development, the producers had
difficulties securing financial support.
It was eventually produced with a budget between US$100 million and US$146.7 million provided by
independent sources, making it one of the most expensive independent films ever produced.
Filming for Cloud Atlas began in September 2011 at
Babelsberg Studio in Potsdam-Babelsberg, Germany.
It premiered on 8 September 2012 at the 37th Toronto International Film Festival, and was
publicly released on 26 October 2012 in conventional and IMAX cinemas.
Critics were polarized, causing it to be included on
various "Best Film" and "Worst Film" lists.
It was nominated for a Golden Globe Award for Best Original Score for Tykwer
(who co-scored the film), Johnny Klimek, and Reinhold Heil.
It received several nominations at the Saturn Awards, including Best
Science Fiction Film, and won for Best Editing and Best Make-up.
The film explores themes of future, artificial intelligence (a.i.),
based on novel or book, san francisco, california, clone.
The tone is emotional and thought_provoking.